[Music]
Welcome to Business Center launch event
20125 release wave
1. I want to show you new uh piece of
functionality related to value chain and
this time I will explain how value chain
and scope tree automation impacts your
assembly order functionality.
So let's look what we have and what is
value chain scope at all. First before
we started with value chain we had only
sustainability ledger entries for uh
final uh environmental impact reporting
based to uh to authorities and we could
report all entries coming from
sustainability journal and from this
wave from general journal and purchasing
voices. This is what we had. But now
from this wave we introduce new
functionality related to uh value chain.
And what does it mean? We have now new
functionality. We have sustain
sustainability value entry. And this is
very very similar what we have in the
existing value entries inside the
business central. But only difference is
that value entry is related with the
item costs and the sustainability value
entry is related with item
emissions. So everything is started with
the purchase document. you will get this
first uh incoming emission from purchase
documents in this wave only for items.
So uh item charge cannot be applied in
this wave. This is something what we are
planning for the future and then all
these different internal documents
transfer assembly or the production
order can have an impact uh what you're
doing to your sustainability value
entries with a final idea to get all
this information on your finished or
assembly goods uh on your sales invoice.
In this way, we do not support uh
different printouts. We have this
information on post sales invoice
document. But if you want to to print
them, you need to add them manually to
your printouts. In the future, we will
see based on your feedback how you would
like to have this uh intro introduced in
printouts. So in this session, I will be
focused on assembly
orders. And let's see how it impacts.
First I want to emphasize all value
chain works only with the carbon
equivalent. So whatever you enter as
your uh beginning on purchase documents
if you enter carbon and metan and
natrium system will automatically
calculate your carbon equivalent based
on this emissions and emission fee
configuration and in the future system
will use carbon equivalent for all these
value chain
calculations. Okay. In assembling
everything is starting with items and
resources. So you can configure your
sustainability account and your
emissions both of item and resources.
And then when you create assembly order
all these uh emissions will be
transferred to your assembly item and
then when you post you will get
information on assembly order header
calculation and we will use all this
information incoming information on uh
assembly lines. So this is very easy how
system is
working. Final solution is final uh
result is that we will get
sustainability value entry used for
calculation uh of item emission. In this
moment system work only with average
method. Okay let's see how it's
starting. First you need to start with
sustainability setup to find proc
procurement fast tab and then you need
to enable these default values. So you
will use in purchase documents. You will
find default values on items on
resources and what is the most important
you need to enable value chain tracking
field. Without enabling this one what is
important when you post purchase invoice
system will create only per uh
sustainability ledger entry. If you want
to get create a sustainability value
entry together, you need to enable you
need you must enable this field. Without
enabling system will behave as earlier
you will not see any difference in user
experience. But when you enable because
this completed functionality about value
chain is in this moment in public
review. You will get this warning
message that our suggestion will be
first try this functionality in your
sandbox and after you confirm everything
work based on your expectation you can
switch to production
environment. Okay, let's look how is
working in a practice. We are starting
with one item. We will use this item in
assembly document and we already have
stock. We didn't get purchase document
and you can see that we have empty
fields in all emissions here. So what
you can do before that you can uh enter
emissions manually. Maybe you got a
detail emission related to this item by
phone by some other sources. You can
enter manually and you can run calculate
CO2 action. This action applies only if
you didn't have a purchase document. So
only if you want to enter information in
your already existing items without
purchase documents. But once when you
create purchase documents system will
automatically collect information from
your purchase invoice posted purchase
invoice and use automatically
calculation on your carbon equivalent in
the background. So let's make a look how
it's look like in a uh purchase
document. When you open our purchase
documents, you will get your
sustainability account as default
defaulted for these items. And what do
you need to do? You need to get uh
information about your uh carbon about
uh metan. And again, it doesn't need
that you need to have all three gas
emissions. You can use only carbon if
you want. It depends what you want to
track. So okay, you will uh enter all of
them or one of them. And then you will
post a document one. When you post
document, when you open posted purchase
invoice, you will find that we have now
sustainability ledger entry as earlier
and plus sustainability value entry.
When we look in sustainability value
entry, you can see as we had two lines
on the purchase invoice, we will get two
lines here. First line is um uh for uh
this item for 60 and another for 10. So
you will get recalculated uh carbon
accurate per unit. So everything is
here.
Okay, you can see all the details and
let's switch now back to this item when
we had empty values. And you can see as
we had 110 110 and one uh values for gas
emissions on our purchase document
system used them and already
recalculated uh to get carbon
equivalent. In my case emission fee is
uh carbon equate emission fee is 111. So
I wanted to make it easier for you to
understand uh final calculation. So we
just got summarized information in
carbon equivalent. So now we can proceed
with our assembly order. We have
assembly order with these two items we
purchase and we have third line with
resources and I already set it up the
same way as we have in um emissions for
this resource. So everything is already
configured before uh I created assembly
order. So now you can see we have this
uh this new columns total carbo
equivalent and this is keep in mind this
is total not per unit this is total and
then you can look in the quantity and
quantity to assembly quantity is 10. So
this total is related to this 10. This
is what we will consume based on our
total uh quantity what we are planning
to consume to to get uh this final
quantity of 10 assembly items. But as we
have only five, you can remember some of
these values. And once when we post it,
you will see our total consumption will
be less because we didn't consume all
this carbon equivalent. So we consumed
only half of that. So this is what
system did. System calculated only what
is applying for this assembly quantity.
Okay, this is what we uh used in this
assembly order. But let's look what we
have here. If you look even in our
summary, you can find that this is 1,700
something uh carbon a total carbon
equivalent
uh consume in this assembly order. If
you click, you can see in our posting uh
fast tab, the total uh CO2E is
1,726 and per unit because we produced
we assembled five of them. This is
345.20 and we already have
sustainability account number. So this
is what system is doing in the
background. system will consume what you
have from your assembly lines
recalculate and in your new assembly
item uh will be uh will get a new
emission value. If you look now in this
item assembly item 1920 25 so if you
look there you will see that we have
carbo equivalent per unit as I already
show you this assembly order fastab
345.20 20. So this is what we have
there. And you can see that other
default emissions for carbon, metan are
empty because I said we are using only
carbon equivalent and they are disabled
because you cannot enter either of these
values if replenishment tab is uh not
purchased. So in this case this is
assembly order replenishment policy. So
you can uh get carbon equivalent per
unit only calculated in your assembly
orders.
So this is how system is working with uh
value chain scope tree automation and
assembly orders. Um I am inviting you to
watch another sustainability videos
because now we have eight sustainability
videos in this this busy center launch
event but especially three of them
related to value chain automation. If if
you want to understand full scope of
value chain scope three automation you
should uh watch all three of them. Thank
you for watching this video.